Guide to the William S. Burroughs Papers MSS.625
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series II. Correspondence, 1962-2012; 12.99 Linear Feet in 25 manuscript boxes, 1 cassette box, 1 oversize folder, and 2 folders in 2 shared flat boxes; 1 audiocassette
  - Robbins, Jonathan, 1983-1987 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Robinson, Christopher John B., 1981-1987 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Rodley, Chris, 1996-1998 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Rollins, George, 1986-1989 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Rooks, Conrad, 1988 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Rosco, Jerry, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Rubiner, Joel, 1987 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Ryan, Nancy, 1984-1994 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Rynne, Frank, 1992 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Sampas, Jim, 1992-1998 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Sanders, Ed, 1994-1997 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Schneebaum, Tobias, 1985-1993 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Scudder, Roger, 1990 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Seaver, Richard -- Arcade Publishing, 1985-1995 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Secunda, Tony, 1992-1993 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Seidman, Graham, 1995-1997 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Shapiro, Leonard, 1988 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Sharits, Paul, 1975-1987 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Shimomura, Roger, 1989-1997 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Silverberg, Ira, 1985-1997 (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Simon, Kate, 1996 (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Skerl, Jennie, 1984-1996 (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Smith, Dylan and Virginia, 1986-1994 (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Smith, Patti, 1985-1996 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Sobieszek, Robert A. -- Los Angeles County Museum of Art, 1993-1996 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Solomon, Carl, 1989-1991 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Southern, Terry, 1987-1995 (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Spiegelman, Art, 1992 (Box 17, Folder 15)
  - Stanford, David -- Viking Penguin, 1992-1997 (Box 17, Folder 16)
  - Steadman, Ralph, 1995-1996 (Box 17, Folder 17)
  - Stein, Chris, 1986-1997 (Box 17, Folder 18)
  - Steinbeck, John IV and Nancy, 1986-1994 (Box 17, Folder 19)
  - Stern, Jacques, 1982 (Box 17, Folder 20)
  - Stern, Richard, 1995 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Stevenson, Jack, 1974 (Box 17, Folder 22-23, Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Strieber, Whitley, 1989-1996 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - Swales, Peter, 1992-1993 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Takis, 1997 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Theater of All Possibilities, 1985-1991 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Thomas, Jeremy, 1986-1997 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Thompson, Hunter S., 1993 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Tobia, George, 1993-1995 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Tong, Winston, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Turner, William G., 1984-1996 (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Tynan, Jim, 1988 (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Vale, Vale, 1982-1996 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Van, Jed, 1989-1996 (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Van Sant, Gus, 1986-1997 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Vidal, Gore, circa 1995 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Vollmer, Caroline, undated (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Wadsworth, Andy, 1984-1993 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Waits, Tom, 1991-1994 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Waldman, Anne, 1988-1996 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Walsh, Gerry, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Warhol, Andy, 1987-1988 (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Waters, John, 1984-1996 (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Watson, Alan, 1981-1982 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Weinrich, Regina, 1987-1997 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Weissner, Carl, 1988-1993 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Welles, R.K.O., 1987 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - White, Edmund, 1990-1991 (Box 18, Folder 27)
  - White, Michael, 1980-1995 (Box 18, Folder 28, Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Whitehead, Ron, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Whitney Museum of American Art, 1995 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Wilson, Peter L., 1988 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Wilson, Robert A., 1978-1998 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Wilson, Robert M., 1989-1997 (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Wilson, S. Clay, 1982-1997 (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Wilson, Terry, 1981-1994 (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Winston, Paul, 1985-1990 (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Wise, Damon, 1993-1996 (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Woodard, David, 1985-1997 (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Woods, Eddie, 1989-1992 (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Woolman, David, 1992-1997 (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Yardley, Robert, 1984 (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Zurbrugg, Nicholas, 1987-1996 (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - General Correspondence -- A, 1981-1997 (Box 19, Folder 16, Box 20, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence -- B, 1982-1992 (Box 20, Folder 2-6)
  - General Correspondence -- C, 1982-1997 (Box 20, Folder 7-8)
  - General Correspondence -- D, 1981-1997 (Box 20, Folder 9, Box 21, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence -- E, 1985-1995 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence -- F, 1982-1996 (Box 21, Folder 3-4)
  - General Correspondence -- G, 1982-1997 (Box 21, Folder 5-7)
  - General Correspondence -- H, 1981-1997 (Box 21, Folder 8, Box 22, Folder 1-2)
  - General Correspondence -- I, 1983-1994 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence -- J, 1984-1997 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - General Correspondence -- K, 1982-1997 (Box 22, Folder 5-6)
  - General Correspondence -- L, 1982-1997 (Box 22, Folder 7, Box 23, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence -- M, 1981-1997 (Box 23, Folder 2-5)
  - General Correspondence -- N, 1965-1997 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence -- O, 1990-1998 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence -- P, 1982-1997 (Box 23, Folder 8, Box 24, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence -- Q, 1994-1996 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence -- R, 1982-1997 (Box 24, Folder 3-5)
  - General Correspondence -- S, 1981-1997 (Box 24, Folder 6-8, Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 9)
  - General Correspondence -- T, 1982-1997 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - General Correspondence -- U, 1984-1994 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - General Correspondence -- V, 1988-1997 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - General Correspondence -- W, 1982-1997 (Box 25, Folder 4-5)
  - General Correspondence -- Y, 1992-1995 (Box 25, Folder 6)
  - General Correspondence -- Z, 1987-1997 (Box 25, Folder 7)
  - General Correspondence -- Unidentified, 1986-1995 (Box 25, Folder 8)
- Series III. Writing, 1968-2008; 11.81 Linear Feet in 23 manuscript boxes, 1 cassette box, and 1 folder in 1 shared flat box; 11 audiocassettes; 4.1 Megabytes in 434 computer files
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically into seven subseries and alphanumerically within each one.
  This series consists mostly of manuscript pages and drafts of Burroughs' writing, both published and unpublished. Publications include The Black Rider: The Casting of the Magic Bullets, My Education: A Book of Dreams (1995), and The Letters of William S. Burroughs, Vol. 1: 1945-1959 (1993), as well as shorter works, including "Death Fiend Guerrillas", Ghost of Chance, "The Johnson Family", and Tornado Alley. Unpublished works consist of materials used for readings and events, daily journals, and many untitled manuscripts. Although many of the published works in the collection might not be as well known as some of Burroughs' other works, they all illustrate his signature semiautobiographical style (autobiographical in some cases here) and his lengthy revision process.
  - Subseries III.A. The Black Rider: The Casting of the Magic Bullets, 1988-2003; 2.60 Linear Feet in 5 manuscript boxes and 1 cassette box; 8 audiocassettes
    This series consists of materials related to The Black Rider: The Casting of the Magic Bullets (first performed in 1990), an opera based on a German folktale, co-created by the theater director Robert Wilson, musician Tom Waits, and Burroughs. Materials include correspondence between the collaborators, correspondence with various theaters, drafts and manuscripts of the text, musical compositions, research materials, notes, German translations, theater programs, and audio recordings of rehearsals and songs.
    - Audio Recordings
      - The Black Rider 1-2, August 6, 1989 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0006)
      - The Black Rider 3-4, August 6, 1989 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0005)
      - The Black Rider 5-6, August 6, 1989 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0007)
      - The Black Rider 7-8, August 6, 1989 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0008)
      - Full Dress Rehearsal -- Part 1, March 29, 1990 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0002)
      - Full Dress Rehearsal -- Part 2, March 29, 1990 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0003)
      - Tom Waits Songs -- Phase 1, 1989 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0009)
      - Video Review, February 1990 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0004)
    - Background Material -- Der Freischutz -- Folk Legend Synopsis and Opera Script, 1988 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Book Project, 1989 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Business Charts and Production List, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Contracts, 1989-1993 (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 25, Folder 13-14, Box 26, Folder 1-7)
    - Itineraries, 1989-1990 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Press and Reviews, 1989-1993 (Box 26, Folder 9-10)
    - Press Release by Burroughs, 1990 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Scenario -- Full Text, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Scene Notes -- James Grauerholz, Greg, Robert Wilson, and Tom Waits, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Song and Music Lists, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Surtitles, 1993 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Synopsis, 1989 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Text and Speech Lists and Counts, 1989-1990 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Texts
      - Early Notes and Drafts, 1988-April 1989 (Box 27, Folder 8-9)
      - Preliminary, August 1989 (Box 27, Folder 10-11)
      - Draft Fragments and Revisions, September 1989 (Box 27, Folder 12-14)
      - Full Draft, September 26, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 1-3)
      - New Pages and Notes, October 1989 (Box 28, Folder 4)
      - German Translation -- Udo Breger, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 5)
      - German Translation -- Wolfgang Wiens, 1989 (Box 28, Folder 6)
      - Revisions with Songs -- German and English, January-February 1990 (Box 28, Folder 7-8)
      - New Pages, February 1990 (Box 28, Folder 9)
      - New Pages, March 1990 (Box 28, Folder 10)
      - New Translations with Lyrics, April-May 1990 (Box 28, Folder 11)
      - Standard American Text -- First Draft, May 20, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 12)
      - Standard American Text -- Second Draft, May 22, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 13, Box 29, Folder 1)
      - English and German Translations -- Possibly Final Versions, circa 1990 (Box 29, Folder 2)
      - Standard American Text -- Third Draft, 1991 (Box 29, Folder 3)
      - Wolfgang Wiens -- German Version, 2003 (Box 29, Folder 4)
      - Theater Programs, Poster, and Tickets, 1990-1993 (Box 29, Folder 5)
      - Video Reviews -- Read-Along English Text and Notes, 1989-1990 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Subseries III.B. Everything Lost: The Latin American Notebook of William S. Burroughs, 2007; 0.44 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box
    This subseries includes materials related to Everything Lost: The Latin American Notebook of William S. Burroughs (2007), Burroughs' reflections of his four years in Latin America, specifically Mexico City, Ecuador, Colombia, and Peru. Materials include photocopies of the first proof and transcript.
    - First Proof -- Photocopy, May 2007 (Box 29, Folder 7)
    - Transcript and Fair Copy -- Photocopy, May 2007 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Subseries III.C. The Letters of William S. Burroughs, Vol. 1: 1945-1959, 1991-1994; 1.75 Linear Feet in 4 manuscript boxes; 3.75 Megabytes in 422 computer files
    This subseries includes materials related to The Letters of William S. Burroughs, Vol. 1: 1945-1959 (1993), a collection of Burroughs' correspondence edited and introduced by Oliver Harris. Materials consist of various drafts of the letters, footnotes, acknowledgements, and the introduction, in both analog and digital formats. Also included are editor's notes and questions, word counts, reviews, and correspondence with publishers.
    - Correspondence and Notes
      - Electronic Records, June-October 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_4
      - Paper Records, 1991-1992 (Box 29, Folder 9)
    - Drafts
      - Burroughs' Review Copy, March 1991 (Box 29, Folder 10, Box 30, Folder 1)
      - Individual Letters -- Possible First Draft, March-June 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_6
      - Second Draft with Additions
        - Annotations by Allen Ginsberg, May-July 1991 (Box 30, Folder 2-7)
        - Electronic Records, June 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_2
      - Second Draft with Partial Revisions and Notes, June-August 1991 (Box 30, Folder 8)
      - Introduction
        - Initial Drafts, July-August 1991 (Box 30, Folder 9)
        - Revised, March 1992; FA_MSS_625_ER_7
      - Acknowledgements, October 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_1
      - Copyright Page, October 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_3
      - Footnotes, October 1991
        - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_625_ER_5
        - Paper Records, October 1991 (Box 30, Folder 10)
      - Third Draft -- First Submission -- Incomplete, October 1991 (Box 30, Folder 11, Box 31, Folder 1)
      - Third Draft with Revisions, October 1991
        - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_625_ER_9
        - Paper Records, October 1991 (Box 31, Folder 2)
      - Title Page, October 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_10
      - Fourth Draft, October 1991 (Box 31, Folder 3-7)
      - Post-Fourth Draft Revisions, January-March 1992; FA_MSS_625_ER_8
      - Fifth Draft, May 1992 (Box 31, Folder 8-9, Box 32, Folder 1-2)
    - Galleys, May 1992 (Box 32, Folder 3-6)
    - Paperback Cover Proof, 1994 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Press and Reviews, 1993-1994 (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Proofs -- Unrevised, 1993 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - Word Counts and Edit Checklist, 1991
      - Electronic Records, FA_MSS_625_ER_11
      - Paper Records (Box 32, Folder 10)
  - Subseries III.D. My Education: A Book of Dreams, 1983-1996; 2.63 Linear Feet in 6 manuscript boxes; 262 kilobytes in 6 computer files
    The subseries My Education: A Book of Dreams consists of materials related to this collection of Burroughs' dreams, published as a novel/memoir in 1995. Materials include various drafts, in both analog and digital formats, notes, correspondence with publishers, inserts and additions, reviews and press, and cover art.
    - Correspondence, 1992-1995 (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Cover Proofs, 1994-1996 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Drafts
      - First Draft -- Incomplete
        - Electronic Records, September-October 1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_12
        - Paper Records, January-September 1991 (Box 32, Folder 13)
      - Fragments, January 1992 (Box 33, Folder 1)
      - Additional Material, April-May 1992; FA_MSS_625_ER_13
      - First Draft -- Complete, May 1992 (Box 33, Folder 2-3)
      - Additional Material, June 1992 (Box 33, Folder 4)
      - Additional Material -- Uncorrected, August 1992 (Box 33, Folder 5)
      - First Draft with Additions, August 1992 (Box 33, Folder 6-8, Box 34, Folder 1)
      - Additional Material and Inserts, December 1992 (Box 34, Folder 2)
      - Partial Revisions, September 1993 (Box 34, Folder 3)
      - First Draft -- Edited, October 1993 (Box 34, Folder 4-6)
      - Cut Pages, February 1994 (Box 34, Folder 7-8, Box 35, Folder 1-5)
      - Cut Pages -- Revised, February 1994 (Box 35, Folder 6, Box 36, Folder 1-2)
      - Typed by Viking, February 1994 (Box 36, Folder 3-4)
    - Original Manuscripts and Notes, 1983-1994 (Box 36, Folder 5-9, Box 37, Folder 1)
    - Page Proofs, June-July 1994 (Box 37, Folder 2-3)
    - Page Proofs -- Cover Flap and Frontispiece, September-October 1994 (Box 37, Folder 4)
    - Press and Reviews, 1994-1995 (Box 37, Folder 5)
    - Proposed Titles, undated (Box 37, Folder 6)
  - Subseries III.E. Novels, 1977-2001; 1.73 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 cassette box; 3 audiocassettes
    This series consists of materials related to Burroughs' novels, some of which are his most well-known, such as Naked Lunch and Queer. Materials include the audio abridgment transcript of Queer; audio recordings and transcripts for the audiobook version of Junkie: Confessions of an Unredeemed Drug Addict, or Junky; excerpt typescripts for Naked Lunch and Nova Express; and drafts and cover art for The Place of Dead Roads, Port of Saints, and The Western Lands.
    - Cities of the Red Night -- Protagonist Description and Cover Proof for Reissue, 1994 (Box 37, Folder 7)
    - Junkie: Confessions of an Unredeemed Drug Addict, or Junky
      - Audiobook -- Audio Recordings
        - First Edit -- Pages 1-15, May 9, 1996 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.001)
        - First Edit -- Pages 152-182, July 12, 1996 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0011)
        - Prologue Edit, July 15, 1996 (Box 53, Audiocassette 625.0012)
      - Audiobook -- Correspondence and Notes, 1995-1996 (Box 37, Folder 8)
      - Audiobook -- Cover Proof, 1996 (Box 37, Folder 9)
      - Audiobook -- Prologue -- Text Edits, circa 1996 (Box 37, Folder 10)
      - Audiobook -- Text Final Draft -- Unrevised, April 1996 (Box 37, Folder 11, Box 38, Folder 1)
      - Cover -- Paperback Edition, circa 1977 (Box 38, Folder 2)
      - Junky: The Definitive Text of "Junk" -- Correspondence and Notes, 2001 (Box 38, Folder 3)
      - Screenplay by James Grauerholz -- Based on Treatment by Grauerholz and Burroughs -- Rewrite, 1994 (Box 38, Folder 4)
      - Screenplay by Terry Southern -- First Draft, undated (Box 38, Folder 5)
    - Naked Lunch
      - Audiobook -- Review, April 1996 (Box 38, Folder 6)
      - Excerpts -- Typescripts, undated (Box 38, Folder 7)
    - Nova Express -- Excerpt -- Typescript, undated (Box 38, Folder 8)
    - The Place of Dead Roads
      - Copy and Reading Materials, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 9)
      - Copy and Alternative Materials, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 10)
      - Material to Be Added, undated (Box 38, Folder 11)
      - Possible Drafts, 1981-1982 (Box 38, Folder 12-15, Box 39, Folder 1)
      - Reissue -- Cover Proof, 1994 (Box 39, Folder 2)
      - "The Sky Is Thin as Paper Here" -- Reading Copy, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 3)
    - Port of Saints -- Drafts, undated (Box 39, Folder 4)
    - Queer
      - Audio Abridgement -- Text Final Draft, 1996 (Box 39, Folder 5)
      - Cover -- Paperback Edition, 1985 (Box 39, Folder 6)
      - Screenplay by David Ohle -- Manuscript and Correspondence, 1995 (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - The Western Lands
      - Draft -- Numbered Copies, 1984 (Box 39, Folder 8)
      - Miscellaneous Texts, 1983 (Box 39, Folder 9)
      - Portions Considered for Cat Book, 1985-1986 (Box 39, Folder 10)
      - Possible Drafts, 1982 (Box 39, Folder 11)
      - Proof Excerpt -- Paperback Edition, 1987 (Box 39, Folder 12)
      - Reviews, 1988 (Box 39, Folder 13)
  - Subseries III.F. Short Stories, Novellas, Essays, and Other Published Material, 1968-1997; 2.65 Linear Feet in 3 manuscript boxes and 1 folder in 1 shared flat box; 44 kilobytes in 4 computer files
    This subseries focuses on Burroughs' shorter published works, including novellas, short stories, essays and essay collections, and contributions to other authors' publications. Materials consist of manuscript drafts (both analog and digital) and notes for "Death Fiend Guerrillas", The Cat Inside, Ghost of Chance, "The Johnson Family," and Tornado Alley. Also included are drafts and correspondence with authors and publishers for introductions, prefaces, and contributions for other publications, such as Anne Waldman's The Beat Book (1996).
    - The Adding Machine: Selected Essays
      - Excerpts and "When Did I Stop Wanting to Be President" -- Reading Versions, February 1995 (Box 39, Folder 14)
      - "The Name Is Burroughs" -- Drafts and Final Version, 1982-1986 (Box 39, Folder 15)
      - Review, 1986 (Box 39, Folder 16)
    - "Ah Pook Is Here" -- Draft for Reading, circa 1978-1979 (Box 40, Folder 1)
    - The Beat Book -- Edited by Anne Waldman -- Proofs of Burroughs' Contribution, 1995 (Box 40, Folder 2)
    - "Bugger the Queen" -- Draft, January 1978 (Box 40, Folder 3)
    - "Burroughs Academy: Bulletin 4 Scientology Revisited" -- Reprint from Mayfair, January 1968 (Box 40, Folder 4)
    - The Cat Inside
      - Drafts, 1985 (Box 40, Folder 5)
      - First Draft, June 1985 (Box 40, Folder 6-7)
      - Final Draft, March 1986 (Box 40, Folder 8)
    - "Death Fiend Guerrillas" -- Drafts, 1990-1991; FA_MSS_625_ER_14
    - Exterminator! -- Paperback Cover Proofs and Review, circa 1973-1979 (Box 40, Folder 9)
    - "Face to Face: William Burroughs Observes Its Rites…" -- Oui -- Photocopy, August 1973 (Box 40, Folder 10)
    - Ghost of Chance
      - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 40, Folder 11)
      - Drafts, 1986-1989 (Box 40, Folder 12-14)
      - Manuscript -- Copyedited, 1995-1996 (Box 40, Folder 15)
      - Reviews, 1995-1996 (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - "How You Stop Smoking" -- Book Review in Form of a Television Ad of Hope to Stop Smoking by Herbert Brean -- Corrected Copy, 1975 (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Interzone
      - Paperback Cover Proof, 1994 (Box Shared Fales 116, Folder 8)
      - Reviews, 1988-1989 (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Introduction and Interview Typescripts -- Everything Is Permitted: The Making of Naked Lunch -- Edited by Ira Silverberg, December 1991 (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - "The Johnson Family" -- Drafts, 1983-1987 (Box 40, Folder 20)
    - "The Junky's Christmas" -- Typescript, undated (Box 40, Folder 21)
    - "Kerouac" -- English Version with Final Paragraph Restored, circa 1969-1973 (Box 40, Folder 22)
    - Letters to Editors -- Published Versions, 1980-1981 (Box 40, Folder 23)
    - Liner Notes -- Typescript -- Apocalypse Across the Sky by The Master Musicians of Jajouka Led By Bachir Attar and Produced by Bill Laswell, 1992 (Box 40, Folder 24)
    - Preface -- Typescript -- Dr. Benway: A Variant Passage from The Naked Lunch, circa late 1970s (Box 40, Folder 25)
    - "Ports of Entry"
      - Catalogue -- Brion Gysin Exhibition -- The October Gallery -- Photocopy, 1981 (Box 40, Folder 26)
      - Repurposed Text for Event/Lecture/Publication for Ports of Entry: William S. Burroughs and the Arts, 1997 (Box 40, Folder 27)
    - "Ruski" -- Drafts and Possible Alternate Texts, 1984-1988 (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - "Time of the Assassins" Column -- Crawdaddy Magazine
      - "Roosevelt After the Inauguration" -- Incomplete Typescript, December 1976 (Box 41, Folder 2)
      - "Sexual Conditioning" -- Typescript, circa 1976 (Box 41, Folder 3)
      - Untitled -- Published Version, September 1977 (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Tornado Alley
      - Correspondence, 1987-1992 (Box 41, Folder 5)
      - Drafts, 1987-1988 (Box 41, Folder 6-7)
      - Marketing Material and Reprints, 1989-1996 (Box 41, Folder 8)
    - "Twilight's Last Gleamings" -- Restored Drafts, circa 1988 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - "Voices in Your Head" Typescript -- Introduction to You Got to Burn to Shine by John Giorno, 1992 (Box 41, Folder 10)
  - Subseries III.G. Unpublished and Unrealized Projects, 1970-2008; 3.06 Linear Feet in 7 manuscript boxes; 55.5 kilobytes in 2 computer files
    This subseries consists of Burroughs' unpublished work. Materials includes handwritten notes on index cards, journal and dream entries (mostly labeled as "Day to Day"), unpublished manuscripts (mostly typescripts but some handwritten), and manuscripts and correspondence related to unrealized projects, such as a contribution to "The New Gothic," in both analog and digital formats. Many of these materials were used by Burroughs for public readings and other events and include reworkings of possibly published material.
    - "Andy Warhol Shot by Valerie Sola…", 1989 (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - "Back-Up", 1985 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - "Cats", 1982 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - "Celestial Babies of the Mary Celeste" -- The New Gothic -- Edited by Bradford Morrow and Patrick McGrath -- Unrealized Project
      - Correspondence, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 14)
      - Drafts with Revisions
        - Drafts 1A-1B, 1990; FA_MSS_625_ER_15
        - Paper Records, 1990-1991 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - "The CIA Reporter", undated (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - "Cold Hearted Man", circa 1981 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - "Current File", January-March 1988 (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - "Current Material -- Unassigned", 1985 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - Cut-Ups -- Photocopy, 1985 (Box 41, Folder 20)